Guide to the New York Community Trust Records 1919-2024 MS 3246
New-York Historical Society
New York Community Trust records
1919-2024
New-York Historical Society
New York Community Trust
MS 3246
109 Linear feet in 257 archival document boxes (5"x10"x12") and 6 photo boxes (3"x12"x12")
The New York Community Trust records document the history of this public charity from its founding in 1924 through the present. The bulk of NYCT's archives consist of meeting materials, including agendas, minutes, resolutions, proposals, statistics, and other information relevant to grants and grantmaking. The records also include annual reports, press releases, speeches, newsletters, and photographs.
Access Restrictions
Public access to many records is restricted for 50 years following the date the document was created, with the exception of public-facing documents such as newsletters and annual reports, which are unrestricted. Restricted access documents are denoted (RESTRICTED) below.
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the New York Community Trust, 2025.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into five series:
• Series I: Meeting records, 1919-2024 (RESTRICTED)
• Series 2: Funds, grants, investments, 1921-2020 (RESTRICTED)
• Series 3: Historical materials, 1919-2024 (PARTIALLY RESTRICTED)
• Series 4: Program materials, approximately 1967-2022
• Series 5: Media and marketing, 1923-2024
Any gaps in series numeration are intentional.
Biographical / Historical
The New York Community Trust (NYCT) was founded in 1924 based on the Cleveland Foundation, created in 1914 by banker Frederick Goff. Goff envisioned a pool of charitable resources for the betterment of the city. The community foundation model has allowed banks and trust companies to work with professional grantmakers to ensure that funds stay relevant and respond to the challenges of the day.
NYCT is a public charity that serves New York City's five boroughs as well as Westchester, Nassau, and Suffolk Counties through its divisions in Long Island and Westchester. Community Funds, Inc. is NYCT's nonprofit corporate affiliate that holds and invests funds established by donors.
Scope and Contents
Records in the NYCT archive span 1919-2024. The bulk of NYCT's records consist of meeting materials. These materials contain reports, memoranda, proposals, statistics, data, and other information relevant to grants and grantmaking. The meeting dockets contain agendas, minutes, resolutions, and materials distributed to committees before their meetings.
NYCT's history can be accessed in the annual reports, press articles, press releases, speeches, newsletters, and printed materials retained in the archives.
Unfortunately, much NYCT historical material was lost on October 17, 1984 when a fire at Cirker's, 505 West 55th Street, destroyed 171 cartons of NYCT records.
Related Materials
Ralph Hayes served as the first Director of NYCT (1923-1967). His papers are held at Western Reserve Historical Society in Cleveland, Ohio.
Some active files have been retained by the New York Community Trust.
Charities -- New York (State) -- New York.; Charity Organization.; Trusts and trustees -- New York (State) -- New York.; Dockets.; Minutes (administrative records); Annual reports.; Resolutions (administrative records); Wills.; Financial records.; Oral histories (literary genre); Black-and-white photographs.; Color photographs.; Newsletters.; Press releases.; Historical markers -- New York (State) -- New York; Endowments -- New York (State); Community foundations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Community Funds, Inc.
- Series 1: Meeting records (RESTRICTED), 1919-2024
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1 contains meeting agendas, minutes, and information distributed to committee members for review prior to their meetings. Grants made by NYCT are approved by its Distribution Committee. Grants made by Community Funds, Inc. (CFI) are approved by its Board of Directors.
  Arrangement
  Series 1 is organized into three sub-series:
  1.1 Dockets, 1960-2024
  1.2 Minutes, 1919-2023
  1.3 Board resolutions, 1961-2023
  Materials are arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials in Series 1 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
  - Sub-series 1.1 Dockets (RESTRICTED), 1960-2024
    Materials in Sub-series 1.1 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, May 1960-December 1966 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.1)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 1967-March 1970 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.2)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, May 1970-December 1972 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.3)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 1973-December 1974 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.4)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 1975-July 1976 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.5)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, October 1976-December 1977 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.6)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 1978-February 1979 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.7)
    - 1.1.1. Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 1979-February 1980 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.8)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 1980-February 1981 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.9)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 1981-February 1982 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.10)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 1982-February 1983 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.11)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, March 1983-December 1983 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.12)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 1984-October 1984 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.13)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 1984-July 1985 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.14)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, October 1985-June 1986 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.15)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, July 1986-February 1987 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.16)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 1987-December 1987 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.17)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 1988-July 1988 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.18)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, October 1988-February 1989 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.19)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 1989-October 1989 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.20)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 1989-July 1990 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.21)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, October 1990-June 1991 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.22)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, June 1991-February 1992 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.23)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 1992-December 1992 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.24)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 1993-October 1993 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.25)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 1993-July 1994 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.26)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, October 1994-June 1995 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.27)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, July 1995-April 1996 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.28)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, June 1996-February 1997 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.29)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 1997-December 1997 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.30)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 1998-October 1998 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.31)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 1998-June 1999 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.32)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, July 1999-April 2000 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.33)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, June 2000-February 2001 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.34)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 2001-October 2001 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.35)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 2001-June 2002 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.36)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, August 2002-February 2003 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.37)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 2003-October 2003 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.38)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 2003-June 2004 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.39)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, July 2004-February 2005 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.40)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 2005-October 2005 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.41)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 2005-June 2006 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.42)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, July 2006-February 2007 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.43)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 2007-October 2007 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.44)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 2007-June 2008 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.45)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, July 2008-April 2009 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.46)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, June 2009-February 2010 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.47)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 2010-October 2010 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.48)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 2010-July 2011 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.49)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, October 2011-April 2012 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.50)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, June 2012-February 2013 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.51)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 2013-October 2013 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.52)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 2014-October 2014 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.53)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 2014-June 2015 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.54)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, July 2015-April 2016 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.55)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, June 2016-February 2017 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.56)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, April 2017-December 2017 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.57)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 2018-December 2018 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.58)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 2018-July 2019 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.59)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, October 2019-June 2020 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.60)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, July 2020-April 2021 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.61)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, June 2021-December 2021 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.62)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, February 2022-June 2022 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.63)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, December 2022-July 2023 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.64)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, October 2023-April 2024 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.65)
    - 1.1.1 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Distribution Committee/CFI BOD, June 2024-December 2024 (Offsite-box 1.1.1.66)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, March 1982-July 1987 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.1)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, September 1987-March 1989 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.2)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, May 1989-November 1990 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.3)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, January 1991-June 1993 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.4)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, September 1993-November 1995 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.5)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, January 1996-November 1998 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.6)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, January 1999-November 2001 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.7)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, January 2002-May 2005 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.8)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance & Audit Committee, August 2005-May 2009 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.9)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance & Audit Committee, November 2009-May 2013 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.10)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance & Audit Committee, January 2013-May 2014 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.11)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, November 2013-November 2020 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.11)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Finance Committee, January 2021-November 2024 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.12)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Audit Committee, January 2015-April 2021 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.13)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Audit Committee, January 2022-September 2024 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.14)
    - 1.1.3 Dockets: NYCT/CFI: Audit Committee, November 2024 (Offsite-box 1.1.3.15)
    - 1.1.4 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, May 1999-July 2003 (Offsite-box 1.1.4.1)
    - 1.1.4 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, September 2003-December 2007 (Offsite-box 1.1.4.2)
    - 1.1.4 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, February 2008-November 2011 (Offsite-box 1.1.4.3)
    - 1.1.4 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, February 2012-December 2014 (Offsite-box 1.1.4.4)
    - 1.1.4 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, February 2015-November 2018 (Offsite-box 1.1.4.5)
    - 1.1.4 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, March 2019-November 2020 (Offsite-box 1.1.4.6)
    - 1.1.4 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, February 2021-August 2022 (Offsite-box 1.1.4.7)
    - 1.1.4 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, November 2022-December 2024 (Offsite-box 1.1.4.8)
    - 1.1.5 Dockets: NYCT/CFI Marketing Subcommittee, October 1990-March 1995 (Offsite-box 1.1.5.1)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Subcommittee on Suggestion Review, December 1977-January 1988 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.1)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Subcommittee on Suggestion Review, March 1988-May 1993 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.2)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Subcommittee on Suggestion Review, November 1993-November 1997 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.3)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Subcommittee on Fund Purposes, September 1983-January 1991 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.4)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Subcommittee on Fund Purposes, March 1992-November 1995 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.5)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Subcommittee on Fund Purposes, March 1996-November 1998 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.6)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, March 1998-March 1999 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.6)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, March 1999-June 2001 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.7)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, November 2001-March 2003 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.8)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, June 2003-June 2005 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.9)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, November 2005-June 2008 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.10)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, November 2008-June 2011 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.11)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, November 2011-November 2014 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.12)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, March 2015-November 2018 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.13)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes & Suggestion Review Subcommittee, March 2019-March 2023 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.14)
    - 1.1.6 Dockets: Fund Purposes Subcommittee, May 2023-November 2024 (Offsite-box 1.1.6.15)
    - 1.1.7 Dockets: Endowment Committee, July 2006-September 2024 (Offsite-box 1.1.7.1)
    - 1.1.8 Dockets: Membership & Governance Committee, 1988-2023 (Offsite-box 1.1.8.1)
  - Sub-series 1.2 Minutes (RESTRICTED), 1919-2023
    Materials in Sub-series 1.2 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
    - 1.2.1 Minutes: NYCT Trustees Committee, 1919-1937, Sept. 1950, June 1958, 1969-1991 (Offsite-box 1.2.1.1)
      Separated Materials
      Missing 1959-1958 = vol. 2 of 4 black notebooks
    - 1.2.1 Minutes: NYCT Trustees Committee, 1992-2005 (Offsite-box 1.2.1.2)
    - 1.2.1 Minutes: NYCT Trustees Committee, 2006-2024 (Offsite-box 1.2.1.3)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, January 1924-October 1952 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.1)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, April 1953-March 1971 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.2)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, May 1971-July 1981 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.3)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, October 1981-June 1986 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.4)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, July 1986-December 1990 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.5)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, February 1991-December 1993 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.6)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, February 1994-June 1997 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.7)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, July 1997-December 1999 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.8)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, February 2000-December 2001 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.9)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, February 2002-December 2003 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.10)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, February 2004-July 2005 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.11)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, October 2005-April 2008 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.12)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, June 2008-April 2011 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.13)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, June 2011-April 2014 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.14)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, June 2014-December 2016 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.15)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, February 2017-December 2020 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.16)
    - 1.2.2 Minutes: NYCT Distribution Committee, February 2021-September 2023 (Offsite-box 1.2.2.17)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, December 1955-July 1980 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.1)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, October 1980-February 1988 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.2)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, April 1988-June 1991 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.3)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, July 1991-April 1994 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.4)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, June 1994-April 1997 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.5)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, June 1997-December 1999 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.6)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, February 2000-December 2001 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.7)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, February 2002-December 2003 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.8)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, February 2004-July 2005 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.9)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, October 2005-June 2008 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.10)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, July 2008-June 2011 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.11)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, July 2011-April 2014 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.12)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, June 2014-April 2017 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.13)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, June 2017-December 2020 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.14)
    - 1.2.3 Minutes: CFI Board of Directors, February 2021-September 2023 (Offsite-box 1.2.3.15)
    - 1.2.6 Minutes: NYCT/CFI Finance Committee, July 1975-November 2005 (Offsite-box 1.2.6.1)
    - 1.2.7 Minutes: NYCT/CFI Investment Committee, May 1999-May 2023 (Offsite-box 1.2.7.1)
    - 1.2.8 Minutes: Emergency Grants Committee, 2007-2020 (Offsite-box 1.2.7.1)
  - Sub-series 1.3 Board resolutions (RESTRICTED), 1963-2023
    Materials in Sub-series 1.3 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
    - 1.3 Administrative: Table of contents, Master index (Offsite-box 1.3.1, Folder 1)
    - 1.3 Administrative: Affiliates, 1962-2022 (Offsite-box 1.3.1, Folder 2)
    - 1.3 Administrative: Committees, 1973-2018 (Offsite-box 1.3.1, Folder 3)
    - 1.3 Administrative: General, 1969-2023 (Offsite-box 1.3.1, Folder 4)
    - 1.3 Administrative: Pension, 1974-2018 (Offsite-box 1.3.1, Folder 5)
    - 1.3 Program: General administrative, 1965-1992 (Offsite-box 1.3.1, Folder 6)
    - 1.3 Resolution and Declaration (R&D): By-laws, 1963-1999 (Offsite-box 1.3.1, Folder 7)
    - 1.3 Donor-specific funds, general administrative, 1961-2007 (Offsite-box 1.3.1, Folder 8)
    - 1.3 Finance: Banking, general, 1961-2016 (Offsite-box 1.3.2, Folder 1)
    - 1.3 Finance: Investment, 1964-2007 (Offsite-box 1.3.2, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Funds, grants, investments (RESTRICTED), 1921-2020
  Series 2 contains investment performance reports on trustee banks. There are also early records tracking the funds which were held by trustee banks and trust companies and disbursed by NYCT per the donor's instructions.
  The "Wills Books" are typewritten logs with chronological entries containing a variety of information regarding wills for which NYCT handled disbursements.
  The "Purpose Books" and "Fund Fact Sheets" contain information about the donors' intents and instructions regarding their funds. The "Purpose Books" and "Fund Fact Sheets" are arranged alphabetically by fund name.
  The "Outpayments from Fund" and "Liquidated Funds" are ledger sheets which were maintained to track disbursements from funds. They are arranged alphabetically by fund name.
  Materials in Series 2 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
  - Wills books (RESTRICTED), 1921-1963 (Offsite-box 2.1, Folder 1-6)
    Folder 1: Wills book, 1921-1942
    Folder 2: Wills book, 1921-1942
    Folder 3: Wills book, 1935-1948
    Folder 4: Wills book, 1935-1948
    Folder 5: Wills book, 1943-1963
    Folder 6: Wills book, 1943-1963
    Materials in Box 2.1 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
  - Purpose books (RESTRICTED), 1924-1971 (Offsite-box 2.2, Folder 1-7)
    Folder 1: Purpose book, 1924-1971
    Folder 2: Purpose book, 1924-1971
    Folder 3: Purpose book, 1924-1971
    Folder 4: Purpose book 1924-1971
    Folder 5: Purpose book, 1961-1971
    Folder 6: Purpose book, 1961-1971
    Folder 7: Purpose book, Community Funds, Inc., 1961-1969
    Materials in Box 2.2 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
  - Fund fact sheets; Summary of investments (RESTRICTED), 1974-1982; 1990-2005 (Offsite-box 2.3, Folder 1-7)
    Folder 1: Fund fact sheets, A-K, 1974-1978
    Folder 2: Fund fact sheets, L-Y, 1974-1978
    Folder 3: Fund fact sheets, A-F, 1974-1982
    Folder 4: Fund fact sheets, G-R, 1974-1982
    Folder 5: Fund fact sheets, S-Y, 1974-1982
    Folder 6: Summary of investments, December 1990-December 2000
    Folder 7: Summary of investments, March 2001-September 2005
    Materials in Box 2.3 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
  - Outpayments from fund (RESTRICTED), 1932-1967 (Offsite-box 2.4, Folder 1-6)
    Folders 1-2: Outpayments from fund, A-G
    Folders 3-4: Outpayments from fund, H-R
    Folders 5-6: Outpayments from fund, S-Z
    Materials in Box 2.4 are restricted for 50 years after the creation date of the document.
  - Liquidated funds; Trusteed funds; Reports on financial statements (RESTRICTED), 1930-1966; 1968-1972; 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 2.5, Folder 1-11)
    Folders 1-2: Liquidated funds, 1930-1966
    Folder 3: Liquidated funds, 1950-1965
    Folder 4: NYCT – Trusteed funds, year ended December 31, 1968
    Folder 5: NYCT – Trusteed funds, year ended December 31, 1969
    Folder 6: NYCT – Trusteed funds, year ended December 31, 1970